[sighs]
[magical chime]
[thud & grunt]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[magical chime]
[gasps]
[LARA] My prince?
[♪ opening music begins]
[♪ opening music ends]
Why did I turn into
a mermaid again?
-What did you say?
-Only one person saw her.
I covered it up, but-—
And then I turned back
and had legs again.
Who saw you turn into a mermaid?
[magical chime]
Apparently some guy
who looked like a prince.
What?
He only looked
like him a little bit.
Anyway, why did I
turn into a mermaid?
You changed because your
heart was deeply moved.
[gasps]
You must have felt the
same 200 years ago,
in that moment when
you were about to unite
with the prince in love.
But everything is
different this time.
Sure, of course. Maybe,
were you flustered?
That's it.
In any case, there must
be a significant reason.
You can't rule out the
possibility that he's
the one with whom
you'll find true love.
I just got scared when
I saw his familiar face.
He's not the one
I'm destined for.
[gasps]
-Here.
-Huh?
My clothes are in here.
That day,
when you dove into Lake Biwa
and just left without
coming back.
You dove into Lake Biwa?
Also, who is this person?
Beats me. I thought
he was a customer.
Um, well, thank you.
I'm Luca.
Hmm?
I'm... Luca.
Yeah.
-Your name, please?
-Huh?
Lara.
Oh.
[♪ cheerful music]
Does everyone know
you're a mermaid?
Ah! No, and don't tell anyone!
Of course I won't. People
would think that was weird.
Okay, give me your contact info.
Contact info?
I don't have any contact infos.
-Huh?
Ah?
[LUCA] This is mine.
Try to get in touch.
[♪ cheerful music]
[mysterious whoosh]
[gasps]
[♪ cheerful music continues]
[sighs]
What a strange handsome guy.
-Mari, what do I do?
-Umm...
Here, you can use this.
It's my dad's old phone.
[both hum]
What's wrong?
I won't allow a mermaid and
a human to fall in love.
I wonder...
Is this really the best
way I could be
looking for my potential prince?
[WITCH] Hmm...
I don't know what Lisa
told you exactly, but
the only way to bring
the light back to your family
is to find true love.
But only with... a human.
Hmm, but...
Do you want to send a message?
Just tap here and speak,
and it'll write what you say.
[LARA] Lara.
TODAY
LARA
-Yeah, there you go.
-So then what do I do next?
LARA
WHAT SHOULD I DO NEXT?
Huh?
-No, your finger!
-Huh?
Huh?
[beeps]
[gasps]
Hey, let's meet up.
LUCA
COME SEE ME.
[MARI] Meeting up, just the two
of you? That's a date!
IT'S A DATE.
Oh no, take your
finger off, hurry!
Oh, what should I do?
Here!
This Saturday at 10 AM, the
terrace at Lake Biwa.
[BOTH] What?!
[children shouting]
Oh, hello!
It's good to see you.
[LUCA] This way.
[Lara gasps]
So where... where are we going?
[WOMAN] Also at the summit,
you will experience
breathtaking -—
-...fun, dear.
-Yeah!
[Lara gasping and screaming]
[Lara pants]
Why are we so
high up a mountain?
They said it was going to
be sunny today.
-We should go higher up.
-[gasps]
[indistinct chatter]
I wonder how she is.
-Alright, let's get started.
-[ALL] Right!
[LUCA] It's okay.
We'll be there soon.
[LARA] Who are you?
What do you do?
I go to school.
[LARA] And outside school?
-I do all sorts, I guess.
-All sorts?
-Having fun riding the lift?
-Having fun?
I guess, but where are we going?
The view up there
is really beautiful.
So then you like
beautiful views?
Yeah, I suppose.
I like beautiful things, yes.
[LARA] Beautiful things?
You're disgusting with
that ugly, hideous form!
[gasps]
I mean, when I say beautiful,
it comes in many forms.
Let's talk about it
some other time.
We'll be there soon.
I hope you'll like the view.
[eerie whoosh]
The weather forecast
is totally off.
[gasps]
[wind howls]
Thanks for your patience.
You're waiting on 2 curry
buns, is that right?
Thank you.
I see now.
You're not really that
person, are you?
[Luca gasps]
[LARA] Ah!
Are you okay?
[Luca groans]
Thank goodness!
The food's okay!
I'm starving, so I'm
glad you saved them.
Wait! Both of them? Aren't
you going to share them?
Apparently, this is what
they call a date.
To be honest, I didn't
really understand it,
but for some reason,
from that day on,
Luca started getting
in touch with me.
DONE WITH SCHOOL
ARE YOU WORKING TODAY?
CAN I SEE YOU?
JUST FINISHED.
BE RIGHT THERE.
[♪ cheerful music]
YESTERDAY WAS FUN.
I'LL SEND YOU THE
BIWAKO TERRACE PICS LATER.
THANKS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THE LAUNDRY.
I BROUGHT SOME SNACKS
FOR YOU FROM KYOTO.
I'LL BE RIGHT OVER.
[♪ cheerful music ends]
GOOD NIGHT, LARA.
Maybe he can't sleep
until he says good night.
So come on, tell me,
what do you think of Luca?
Oh well,
at first I was scared,
but...
now I feel like he's somehow
different from that guy.
[MARI] Hmm.
Huh?
THERE'S A PLACE I WANT
TO SHOW YOU NEXT TIME.
I must confess, you're the first
person I've ever brought here.
Oh.
It's a secret place. Even my
friends haven't been here.
And I'm only showing this
place to you and nobody else.
Okay.
[gasps]
[LEO] Oh wow!
Leo.
I told you not to
come over here.
So it really is a girl.
My name's Leo. Can you
tell me your name, please?
I'm Lara.
[LEO] You are so cute!
You're way too good
for my brother.
Huh?
You might think my brother is
good-looking, but be warned
he's also pretty
clueless as well.
-[LUCA] Leo.
-Yes, bro.
His paintings are terrible too.
Bye, Lara.
Don't hold back.
Tell him they're terrible.
It really is for his own good.
They're not that terrible.
[LARA] So did you paint that?
What is this place?
I wanted to show you this room.
Huh?
[♪ soft guitar music]
What a mysterious room.
Is this-—
-What is this exactly?
-This guy.
-Oh, and this?
-A wet dog.
-What's this one?
-That's the real me.
Oh, but then is that
how you see yourself?
The thing is,
yes, I have a fondness for
beauty, but that doesn't always
refer to things you
can see with your eyes.
True beauty comes from the
heart. It's to be discovered
and felt.
I need to paint it and
preserve that beauty.
[wind howls]
So...
the very first moment I saw you,
I wanted to paint you, Lara.
And then, I wanted to
discover more and more
of your radiant and
unmistakable beauty.
I think you're
incredibly beautiful.
And that's why.
[gasps]
[♪ soft guitar music]
Lara...
I wanted you to see what I see.
[♪ soft guitar music continues]
[Lara laughs]
What-— what's so funny?!
So sorry.
Then why are you laughing?
I mean, I've never seen
anything like it.
Well, I've just not
finished it yet.
I do think it's a good painting.
Well, you know,
I need to add more colors.
[gasps]
[eerie whoosh]
[Lara pants]
[Luca pants]
-What happened back there?
-[LARA] That-— that dagger.
-Lara?
-I'm sorry.
I just need to be left
alone right now.
Lara! Please come back soon!
I-— I would like to
finish the painting.
Welcome back.
You're pretty late.
So, how was it?
Huh?
ARE YOU OKAY?
I WANT TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
SORRY.
I'LL CHECK IN AGAIN.
Hmm.
GOOD NIGHT.
[LISA] So then, the witch
has already noticed us.
If we try to get close to Lara,
she'll surely drive us away.
-So, let's just go there and-—
-No.
There's another way.
I'll get Lara back no
matter what it takes
before it's too
late for all of us.
I don't want this, so you can
have my portion.
-Lara?
-No, thanks. I'm good.
-[MARI] Uh...
-[YOSHIYA] Hmm?
Fireworks show is next week.
[BOY] That's right!
Shall we go?
-Going with that girl, Luca?
-Nope.
How many girlfriends have
you had now?
Zero.
Must be someone you like, right?
[alarm beeping]
[beeping]
[sighs]
CAN I CALL YOU TONIGHT?
[LISA] Only when the chosen
princess feels pure, true love
does a radiant light shine
from the depths of her heart.
[magic sound]
[LARA] I've fallen in love
with a human.
I've fallen in love with you.
[gasps]
[♪ ethereal music]
[DAGGER] Tell me, why are
you rejecting me?
[LARA] What?
Tell me,
why won't you love me?
[LARA] Was that?
The dagger?
I want to devour...
that soul of yours.
[gasps]
I want to pierce it...
the prince's heart.
I want to devour.
I want to devour!
[♪ tense music]
[LARA] I had completely
forgotten.
That day,
the pure light of love
within my heart
transformed into a blade.
That light from my heart,
it should be born out of love.
So why?
I'm not sure.
But...
[magical sound]
if this thing is supposed
to be my heart,
then it might end up hurting
someone, or even worse.
Does that bother you?
Come on, you're worried too.
I just thought that maybe...
she'd finally met her prince.
What's that?
[MARI] Let me guess, you've
never seen fireworks?
Huh?
I watch it here with my
family every single year.
I see.
Some people go with friends,
and some with close friends.
Would you like to
go with anyone?
So... do you want to
come this year then?
You seem a little
down lately, bro.
Did Lara dump you or somethi-—?
Huh?
[sighs]
[panting]
[♪ soft guitar music]
[MARI] Lara!
Mari.
Luca, he was just standing
at the overpass crying.
I can't see him anymore.
-You can't leave it like this.
-This is the only way.
So you're just going to walk
away and leave him like that?
-A-—
-No, Mari. You're right.
I'll go and end it properly.
[LARA] Luca!
Lara! I-—
Have you been waiting
here all along?
I don't know.
[LARA] So why are you
making that long face?
Did you really want to
paint me that much?
Is it because I'm a mermaid?
Uh.
Getting close to somebody
like me isn't the
same as getting close
to another human.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
I-— I can't see you anymore!
[♪ soft guitar music]
I see.
I understand.
[sighs]
[♪ soft guitar music]
[thud]
[gasps]
[♪ soft guitar music continues]
Luca?
At first I was interested
because you were a mermaid,
but now... that's all changed.
And I know, even though you
don't like me because I'm human,
and that you don't want
to see me anymore, I'm-—
sorry, Lara.
I like you because you're you.
[sighs]
[LARA] Maybe,
I've been waiting to
hear those words
my entire life.
Thank you.
[♪ closing music begins]
Translation: Sachiko Takahashi
Timing: Andy Ellis
Editing and Typesetting:
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control: Riley Dalton
Translation Check:
Sriram Gurunathan
I know now.
I want to get closer
to this person!
[♪ closing music ends]
- [LARA] We're home!
- [MARI] Hey!
-[MAKOTO] Ah, Lara!
-You're home late.
Weren't the fireworks
just wonderful?
Yeah, they always are.
[chuckles]
TO BE CONTINUED